# **Jon Shamir**

#### ionshamir.com

#### **Summary**

My interests lie at the intersection of technology and visual arts: computer graphics, typography, generative art, machine learning, data visualization and more. I love working on projects that combine different fields and use technology in new and interesting ways.

I have more than a decade of professional experience with various technologies and mediums. Previously worked for small and medium-sized startups, as a freelancer and on academic projects.

# **Professional experience**

# 2019-2021 - Teaching Computer Graphics at the Hebrew University

- Built the practical side of the course from the ground up, teaching Computer Graphics in a more engaging way using the real-time interactivity of the Unity 3D game engine.
- Created 12 lectures with over 500 slides including custom illustrations & animations, 5 coding exercises involving subjects such as Subdivision Surfaces, Ray-Tracing, Shading and Texturing.
- Taught the students remotely and graded their assignments.

# 2018-2020 - Freelance web developer

Designed & developed websites and web applications for several local companies.

## <u>2016-2018 - SAGA, cryptocurrency startup - Lead frontend developer</u>

• Developed company homepage & customer-facing products. Javascript with React, Redux, SASS.

## 2014-2016 - Mobli, social media startup - Senior frontend developer

Frontend developer & team lead on several new projects at the company, including:

- EyeIn plugin for articles (e.g. for news websites). displays relevant media from social networks in real time. Backbone and vanilla JS.
- Galaxia social network application. Designed & developed a management system with React + Flux. Developed an interactive 3D landing page with WebGL + THREE.js.

## 2010 - 2014 - Mandatory Military Service at 8200 intelligence unit

- Completed "Matam" course with honors.
- Developed Python scripts for automation & workflow improvement. Taught technical subjects.
- Designed & developed a web-based data management and analysis system. Received 2013 outstanding intelligence project award. PHP, MySQL, Apache, Javascript HTML & CSS.

#### Education

#### 2018-2021 - B.Des. in Visual Communications, Bezalel Academy of Art and Design

- Courses include Design Thinking, Typography, Illustration, Animation and Game Design.
- Received excellence award in 2019.

## <u>2016-2018 - B.Sc. in Computer Science, Hebrew University of Jerusalem</u>

- Graduated cum laude with a GPA of 96. Received dean's list award.
- Courses include Algorithms, Complexity, Machine Learning, Image Processing, Human-Computer Interaction, Visualization & Sonification.

# <u>2019 - Tel-Aviv University Machine Learning & Graphics Lab</u>

• Worked as a research assistant. Trained and tested generative deep learning models (GANs), ran various experiments dealing with feature-space representation of images.

# 2006-2010 - Newton South High School + Hebrew University High School (Leyada)

• Majored in math, computers, chemistry & robotics.

#### **Tools & Skills**

Javascript - Node, D3, React, Redux, THREE & more CSS, LESS, SASS, Styled Components

Python - PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit Learn, Pandas & more

Unity3D, C#

Shaders - GLSL, HLSL

3D software - Blender, Cinema4D, 3D printing

Adobe CC - Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, After Effects

Drawing & illustration in various mediums

Photography

Some experience:

React Native, next.js

Java, Arduino, C++, C

Objective C, iOS SDK

PHP, SQL, MySQL, Apache